Many ecommerce retailers refrain from investing in their return management process,
and it’s hard to blame them.
Returns can be expensive and time-consuming.
So here are 10 steps for retailers
to improve your returns management process,
start reducing your returns,
and profitably scale your ecommerce business.
Let's get started.
Number 1. Be Lenient with your Return Policies
Your return policies impact your shopper conversion.
If visitors don’t feel confident that they can return products,
they won’t feel confident in purchasing products.
Number 2. Track as Much as You Can
One missing button on a shirt seems minor,
but ten returns with missing buttons in two days
can pull an entire shipment of shirts off the shelf.
Small observations help you discover big problems.
Number 3. Prioritize People and Processes within Your Business
The people and processes within your organization
are every bit as important as the products you sell
or the technology you use.
Keep in mind that the most impactful observations
often come from those who most frequently interact
with products and shoppers.
Number 4. Move Beyond a Spreadsheet
Spreadsheets are helpful
but may not be ideal for advanced product and shopper analyses.
After sifting through endless rows of data,
many retailers struggle to get information from insight.
Leverage the power of return analytics software
to aggregate customer feedback easily
so you can get straight to the insights
and improve your return management process.
Number 5. Embrace Return Optimization
Return Optimization involves leveraging return data
to enhance the shopper experience,
improve operational efficiency,
and grow your profits.
Accept that returns are a part of ecommerce.
You will never eliminate returns,
but you can reduce returns and provide your shoppers
with a smooth return experience.
Number 6. Start with Basic Analyses, then Drill Deeper
To collect real insights, we need more than data.
We need a logical flow of analyses.
Return rates and reasons are an excellent place to start.
They provide a quick summary of your product returns.
Once you identify areas for potential improvement,
zoom into return comments
and customer-level information
to gather precise, contextual feedback.
Number 7. Connect All Parts of Your Business
Returns are often not the responsibility of any single department.
They’re a natural and pervasive part of business in ecommerce,
so the best solutions require a holistic approach.
A culture of collaboration –
supported by mechanized communication –
can align the goals of different teams
and produce better outcomes for both your shoppers and your business.
Number 8. Act Upon Insights Immediately
When you identify a problem,
try to find its cause as efficiently as possible.
One apparel retailer confirmed that the quality of a particular fabric
wasn’t as the factory had specified by looking at return comments.
The team traced the faulty material to the products
and removed the SKU from their website
before more shoppers could encounter the issue.
Number 9. Transform Returns into an Opportunity for Loyalty
As a retailer, you try to maximize the customer experience
in all aspects of your ecommerce site.
The return process should be no different.
You can reimagine returns as a retention opportunity.
The truth is, returns don’t have to cause churn,
and they don’t have to diminish your customer lifetime value.
And lastly, Number 10
Implement Software that Integrates with Existing Systems
To make the most of its impact,
return management software needs to access data stores
within your business.
Make sure its API enables integration with your inventory management
and warehouse management software.
To find the answers to many of the most pervasive questions in ecommerce,
look at the data.
Adopt these ten points,
and you’ll be well-positioned to take control of returns
and capitalize on insights that’ll drive your business forward.
Thank you for watching today's video.
If you haven't already, feel free to hit the like
and subscribe button
as it's free to you and it helps us make more great content like this.
If you want to learn more on this content,
feel free to check out the blog
which I have linked in the description below.
And remember
we do have a podcast.
So check out The Returns Management Podcast by ReturnLogic
on Spotify and all your other favorite podcast channels
and i'll see you guys on the next video.